so Alexander Bart hi there Andrew
Sweeney is an amazing guy I was gonna
say and here are some of his books
Digital libido
Cynthia ISM the future iike trilogy
co-authored with Jen so nervous first of
all you want you believe that we need to
come up with a grand narrative or we're
screwed if I understand correctly and
that perhaps the key to this perhaps the
key to saving ourselves in this very
dangerous period has something to do
with shamanism right yeah there's a
shameless shameless are usually pretty
useless and they're sort of stuck out in
the forest and they're cooking there
which is Bruce and things like that
but at times or evolutionary change when
you go through a proper paradigm shift
actually historically the shamanic cast
the four or five percent of the
population belong to the shamanic eyes
are absolutely key made the connectors
when that happens so your theory is that
the shamanic a still exists perhaps led
but less than not in a formal sense or
it has to be created or I think if
anything doesn't have to be formal it's
a shamanic cast the least organized
people you ever find but when they
create institutions to do so to back up
and support truth and truth seeking so
so yeah churches for example or priests
to it before they go corrupt at least
their shamanic cast diplomats are so
many casts medicine and of all kinds um
but also you know the outcasts of
society the the brothel Madam's and the
horse and the executioner's all those
guys belong to the shamanic ass they're
about four to five percent of the
population in any general population you
can measure their personality traits and
one of the most interesting aspects of
each manic is that you don't mind
strangers you don't understand why the
rest of humanity is obsessed with their
sex lives because he just
fuck anything that moves no problem
you don't understand what the rest of
man is obsessed with skin color because
just like why would you care what's
getting called yet it's just skin color
okay this is typically shamanic traits
um which also means that the shaman's
are the ones that used to walk in
between the tribes peacefully because
there were there were sort of outcasts
in their own tribe to begin words if the
intermarrying way they were
communicating with other tribes
nobody was offended or hurt by that
anyway so when you really needed a
peaceful communication between the
tribes you had to go to the Shannons and
this is the case if you started tribes
today we have the last remnants of the
tribes today in the world in New Guinea
Botswana Brazil northern Canada with
units these are the places where I
studied for the past 10 to 15 years
check out what the original tribe was
like that's doing proper anthropology
the great thing today is that you can
then take all the interviews you did
there and you map those communities and
discovered they were the same in the
Arctic and they were the same of the
silver and I were the same of the jungle
meaning we were all the same people
40,000 years ago we're still basically
the same so we've got a model for the
original tribe actually worked now we
can take the data on contemporary human
beings that's called date down through
Paula G there's what scientists do when
they get access to the data silos at
Google in the husband and we discover
the same patterns jump out of the data
we just made study contemporary even B's
because we haven't really changed that's
exactly and it is a liberal in this book
is so instrumental for me and so darkest
to go back to the original nomadic
plastic tribe and check how that worked
what master key was for patriarchy was
what inner and outer circuit were what
the different responsibilities were what
the different archetypes are they're
androgynous ago in between these groups
and of course shamanic cast which is the
borderland between one tribe of the next
one the total population of the planet
never exceeded three million but you
couldn't support more than max three
million people if everybody was running
around trying to find their food over
time it would have been impossible
whereas once you had permanent
settlements we
in turn required written language once
your written language you could create
large-scale prevalent settlements that
actually last for long periods of time
and that's in the river valleys of the
Middle East in China and India and you
can go to Mesopotamia and if written
language really took off for the
Sumerians 5,000 years ago then 4,000
years ago Mesopotamia subnet half the
world's population an enormous
population growth with permanent
settlements okay so once permanent
settlements arrive in history we can
have much larger populations and support
them because we're actually producing
food and the reason we can produce food
which is a higher level of complexity
compared to the searching for food and
hunting means we can all support much
larger populations this is what
triggered the idea of progress and even
mine and and the first thinker who
thinks progress and process was or Astra
that's me yeah mr. Roston philosopher
three thousand seven hundred years ago
in the iranian highlands currently
central asia was way greener than than
it is now
transoxiana the other two river valley
system which is north of the north east
of the east of the caspian sea the
roster appeared in three thousand seven
years ago we formulated a text we just
call the gothis where he basically says
that we're living in a paradigm shift
that's the first time ever anybody
formulated some thought like that and he
said the world is processed the world is
changed we have to adapt new
environments but the current move from
the nomadic to the permanent settlement
means that we have to celebrate the
treatment or the permanent settlement we
said it's much more sustainable in the
long run the larger population we can
build amazing things because also much
much more dangerous right it's much more
it is more dangerous but at least the
rosters succeeded in the sense that he
built a grown-up man phallic fantasy I
was a grown-up mathematics fantasy I'll
you create a better society in the one
you had in the past and this goes back
to exactly the construction of the
original nomadic tribe the original
Matic tribe has two types of
storytelling it has the matriarchy
storage
which is that everything returns to the
same there's seasons there's spring
summer fall winter spring summer fall
and you know it's very feminine that
sense women remember calendars and
birthdays right but that's the basic
store done foundamental one we also tell
to the children we cannot build anything
unless we have that storytelling in
place first that's a basic one of the
magical storytelling or max your Oracle
if you like celebrating the matriarchy
and and this is the foundation for all
storytelling but on top of that soon
this we have some kind of abandoned
society as soon as we have more than we
actually need we can afford to dream no
can afford a dream or something better
and higher than we are right now and
that is connected to it's necessary and
makes the tribe nomadic the French
philosopher Jill de leurs written a lot
about this he calls philosophy no madala
G the importance of time and process and
change in human life and that we have to
move on successfully you need to create
a story it says that we can't stay here
tomorrow if we stay or tomorrow the
enemies will attack us and kill us cause
you're not Laura and there were no food
or no water left
so we that's the exodus you said you're
writing about this is called phallic
storytelling you know what that is the
story about we're gonna get higher and
we're gonna get better
somewhere we all right now he's gonna
we're gonna go to a better place than
this place currently is and that because
we've consumed or our resources hmm and
we live in dry lands attacked by enemies
and we need to get a safer better place
full of abundance because arrived we
need to have this story that tomorrow
morning we need to get on the moon this
is the fat extortion as well the entire
history of philosophy the entire history
theology religion he's always the two
different stories competing with each
other so it's it's a transcendent can i
scan i I just have a thought is it
transcendence against imminence or
something like that yeah you could say
that yeah well it is all imminent
actually original is all them it's not
about going to heaven I think that all
the original story according to Sigmund
Freud himself is that you got the
Patrick pulling the tribe
the Matt jerk pushing the mental case
about pushing that's why caring and
making sure everybody's with you
arises naturally there's a women are
choking superior to men it comes those
colonies those are mostly female
archetypes in the main or archetypes are
more obsessed with getting out to get go
going because they hunt and they also do
the warfare so they can't stay on the
move anyway their circuit it's way
bigger than the inner circle where the
women the masculine circle is bigger if
you go to the image to north encounter
you discover that winter camps and
summer camps the summer camps move in
much smaller areas and they're owned by
metro arts and essentially their child
rearing and berry picking right and then
you've got the larger circuit which is
the winter camps they go much further
they stay with the ice and they kill the
seals so they killed the moose and they
bring the meat back into the tribe that
that's thrown as a pet turkey so they go
into the dangerous unknown so to speak
yeah exactly
men take risks on a love of the women
don't they physiologically in nature
take much larger risk and they also die
at a rate that women don't women die
mostly from child-rearing and childbirth
and take risks when they give birth to
children in the tribe they did in the
entire world until the nineteen sixties
everywhere but men take risks when it
comes to the hunting and the warfare and
just getting out there and spying and
checking out what's happening so you got
the phonics storytelling we would cease
the priesthood needs to get the tribe on
the moon tomorrow mm-hmm then you got
the magical storytelling which is the
story turning about the women of the
children basically there's a container
here safe space in the center run by the
metric but the condition for you to be
part of this container and to be in the
safe space run by the metric is that
when the metric tells you to get on the
move you need to be on the moon because
anybody who's behind the matter or the
tribe moves is dead so that was a
traditional let's say absolute power of
women in the in the matriarchy yeah this
is the funny thing when we've sort of
reinstituting equality in the genders
they will only reinstitute the most
absolutely natural to us it's kind of
weird that men should dominate women or
women should dominate men for that
matter and any culture where that
happens is an inferior culture if you
look at the most superior culture
planet Udine anything you can measure
like education levels income levels etc
you find two groups that stand out and
it's the parsees of India who are
Zoroastrians ironically and and then the
Jews to this room yeah so this cocky and
strong yeah I would call that
complementarity between men and women
rather than better than the other
egalitarianism for the benefit all so
you maximize few talent you maximize
masculine time you also maximize
androgynous talent between the two so
anybody who's born today's an
evolutionary winner you wouldn't be
around unless you had to play the role
that leads to the original tribe that
doesn't necessarily mean it corresponds
to role you play you today we don't know
that yet but at least we can tell you
that anybody born today has a genetic
makeup that actually made sense okay
that also means that we have can go back
to the history of philosophy and we can
go back to the history of theology
religion and discover that if it was
only the phallic storytelling which is
what came out of Egypt do you know the
boy Pharaohs of Egypt disregarded
everything else and only gave one
priority that was building the pyramid
mm-hmm okay completely phallic
completely patrocle without met turkey
without magical storytelling okay that
eventually translate to Platonism among
the Greeks and the West has had the
problem ever since that we are being
obsessed with phonics storytelling so
progress just let me stop a second um so
that's the fellow logo centric critique
of Western society do you think it's
justified in something some kind of a
way we varied on loving the stranger and
I'm doing a lot of work on myself I
think it's your money but I think it's
absolutely wrong maybe at least for
Jared or after the second world war that
was necessary you have to remember that
Derrida was the North African Jew
arrived in France the nineties and we
came out of the horrors of hits are
installing in Europe Hitler installing
art according to Diliberto fake palaces
but they weren't understood as such what
Derrida misinterpreted
was that all phalluses art Hitler
installing they're not bond his own
Jewish religion and study concept of the
my friar
okay you're gonna you're gonna have to
explain why Hitler and sounh or fake
fake phalluses perhaps okay what that
means exactly precise how do you
differentiate between the authentic
fellows whose rare unfortunately and the
fake pharmacist which are many how do
you differentiate between the authentic
Messiah and the fake messiahs okay
the fake palace will give you a short
route to your success he will basically
tell you if you just put on a uniform
and hate something yeah you'll be fine
Hitler did that with June Stalin did
that with a Kulak that's exactly why
Ukrainians and Russians hate each other
until today because Ukrainian kulaks
were made the Jews of Russia according
to Stalin so Mao did the same thing in
China and it did with the Cultural
Revolution one of the biggest disasters
in history Pol Pot did it more than
anybody and this is the interesting
thing
Pol Pot what I did is peach tea in
France in the nineteen sixties at
Sorbonne which he did before he went
home to Cambodia it was a clever that he
did his PhD on Rousseau yeah Nora Marx
well that's what I was I was under the
impression that he was a Marxist like he
learned Marx and that was the whole
story that I wax all he was not a
Marxist then impossibly warm but you
know by the time you reach stall and
there's no marks involved any longer in
Soviet Communism Mao never even studied
smile read fairytale books for little
boys about old Chinese emperors
he wasn't interested and Rousseau
rosales the dominant thinking of Hitler
and Stalin and Mao Pol Pot what unites
all four and that precisely because they
unified the people through an objection
America and we Paul point it was so easy
by the time he had port in the 1970s
he'd unified the Cambodian people around
the hatred of anybody who wore glasses
they would have killed you and I'm
finished and it did he killed one and a
half million people using his ph.d or
ozone okay and you don't blame that on
Marx you don't no you don't think that
Marx was too much of how you had too
much of a shallow so
materialistic view of you know too much
based on power and then class oh I don't
have a problem aterial ISM I'm AM honest
I don't care whether they realities
ultimate the spiritual material is just
one substance he's all interconnected
there are no two substances because you
would have to figure out how they
connect with each other you have two
substances that was almost the cards
problem I'm a radical modest just not to
be no sir just that line it's just that
table just like me I'm a radical -
there's just one substance the universe
is one substance everything is an
attribute of one thing everything is an
attribute to one universe that we know
okay so no but I don't care where this
material no we can just call it
materialism because we usually refer to
that when we speak one substance and I'm
a speculative material is just like some
kids for example and that's that's there
that would work well we need to save
Karl Marx to these because it's unfair
to blame worse on Marx to begin with
because he hated was so the reason why
March became a great thing in 1837
forties was because the French
Revolution was built the result and he's
failed we needed something better and
what Marx toss is the same thing that
Nietzsche does but nature takes
Cartesian individualism to its most
extreme face and he says that you have
to be the aristocrat the noble guy on
your own and to yourself you have to
establish your own ethical substance
well the problem Nietzsche's that he
thinks of human beings as individuals he
was wrong from the very beginning he was
too much of a Cartesian but at least it
celebrated the heroic
you're an only goes to celebrate the
rock have a future in any of my society
we cannot celebrate the victim and
anybody's self victimizes just turned
themselves into their own enemies let's
throw all the social justice worries
around today in the tiny little Hitler's
and Stalin's we have today and they dead
wrong
your soul never works Rosaura cheap
route to success
he's the fast true he's just like bitch
and complain about your condition and
suddenly you're given the great big tip
from the sky the world for state or
consumer society gives you damn Hamburg
or it gives you your money handout and
your problem is solved the big chicken
playing the next day again and you never
ride so you never achieve anything you
become the bottom
Marx hated this mod Mike's Marx called
these guys the lump and proletariat that
wasn't the hero he wrote about know what
Marx it was the same thing that needs to
do it wasn't much was it Marx
romanticizing the lower you know rather
than the higher and so on do you have to
read Marx to get this you know Karl Marx
is different from Jean Jacques also grow
so celebrated at the bottom of
everything because to him anybody was a
blank slate anyway so if you want
glasses you could be killed because you
could train the non-glass wearing people
just there'd be the new upper class
society this is the fantasy this is brew
so this was Robespierre mmm-hmm and
terrible history we had of the West is
platonism and the worst form of
plagiarism is cartesianism and the worst
form of cartesianism is result
mmm-hmm this is what we need to deal
with so maybe Rousseau is that the
devouring mother in a sense exactly
without the father without the father do
very well but I'm still concerned I'm
still concerned I'm so concerned that
Marx is the tyrannical as a tyrannical
vision in some sense but maybe I'm wrong
no I don't think it does because tyranny
arrives when Pat Turkey is led by only
one Patrick mm-hmm right if you look at
military history all guys to get
involved another to learn you must not
trust the one ruler because it's the
Turner no we always divide patriarchy
between one truth production and number
two the physical actual energy that's a
chief King and the priests or if you
want the King and the priests they're
always separated if you unite the King
with the priests to get the current
that's exactly what we in petrol could
keep the two separate you don't need to
do though with the Metro key is usually
only there oh this woman all them all at
the back and she pushes everything
forward but Patrick is wrong but least
two men that's a - I have the rain God
and the Sun God you always keep them
separate in all polytheistic religion or
like that it's fine yeah explain the
rain God in the Sun God I like that
concept but the Sun God usually takes
out one of his eyes he's only got one
eye
he wants wisdom more than anything and
he protects and look after us and he's
got the Falak case he's the father in
front of whom we all perform to get
reality thrown at us mmm okay the rain
god is the warrior who comes home after
the ritual and because he won the war
for us he impregnates the earth that's
why the rain that's the original
that's the first masculine God rain hits
the ground and once the rain hits the
ground and the ground becomes fertile
you need the Sun to give you son on the
fertility for society to grow then we
keep the Sun God and the rain got
separate we keep Jupiter and Mars
separate we keep Zeus and Apollo
separate which I'm not quite sure why
when you bring them together that that
makes makes tyranny I'm not sure if I
understand because you get the corrupt
father who fucks his own sons wives why
that's ignorant he loses a connection he
doesn't listen any longer he thinks he's
both truth absolute truth and he also
thinks he's achieved and at the same
time this is the ultimate platanus dick
fantasy this was the fantasy of the boy
Pharaoh Egypt as the Satya was not
sustainable and that's exactly like that
comes a tyranny that's what dictators
are both at the same time or spiral at
the same time and that's not sustainable
and there's no autonomy no freedom new
thinking no creativity no change no
process just roll absolutely yeah
you get North Korea that way yeah yeah
so so impact rocky you always divide
these two you have to this is the
important lesson militaristically if you
started the Mithraic order that was the
religion of the room Roman military from
Scotland all the way down to Syria had
Mithras everywhere and it was
immediately a quarter that was the
religion of the of the soldiers and they
would have seven grades you'd have to go
through the sixth and seventh grade
shared the top grade the sixth grade was
the chieftain who old respected the
seventh grade was the priest and the
priest would going to celibacy or
possibly castrate himself not to compete
with the chieftain so then the priest
could be above the chieftain and the
ways usually run throughout history is
that the first son of
the chief Chinese the crown prince to
inherit the chief control the second son
is adopted by the monastery and he
becomes the next priest hmm so that's
how Patrick it works and the fundamental
sense that's it worked in any tribal
look that that's exactly what we're
replicating in a functioning society
that has a long-term sustainable model
mm-hmm and what what functioning
societies do you see like maybe we can
move to what's going on right now what
we got out of the racist word thrown us
over the next ten years and stuff like
that but we're gonna have to do proper
cultural studies that's what I do I
study for example I spent a lot of time
in Israel and I started the Jews of
Israel I'm also starting the
Palestinians because that conflict is
completely misunderstood the Jews of
Israel are the original and accomplished
nation mm-hmm the first nation of Israel
history was the was the exodus the
exodus out of Egypt Moses took the
Hebrews to the promised sir
he didn't do that through objection he
was an authentic fellows because he said
we're gonna go to the promised land we'd
you gonna race up and then he built the
totem pole and said this is direction
we're gonna race her it doesn't mean he
did mean to bad-mouth Egypt they
basically told you just just let go of
us
otherwise God will help us we didn't go
we're gonna go through the desert we're
gonna reach the promised town and
establish the first nation in human
history 11 tribes to that territory is
at 12th tribe did not a territory the
shamanic caste the Levites were given
their all the shamanic caste they walked
across all the territories and carried
and held responsibility for truth mm-hmm
that's what the priesthood dust they the
Levites themselves took that role which
the Allah and other eleven tribes had
the different chains mm-hmm but you
definitely divided the chief Chen from
the priests you divided the King in the
priests completely you created the first
nation a federation of tribes
that's what a nation is and the iron is
the Visayan ism came along in the 19th
century as another one of these
nationalistic movements that were born
out of Europe it was by far the most
successful one eventually they
established the State of Israel and it's
the most successful nations they'd ever
according to any measure you like but I
love the Palestinians
- and I go to the West Bank Jordan
Lebanon I go to the buying see you up on
the sentence the Palestinian national
identity was invented in the 1960s it's
the most modern of them all and to me
it's the Palestinians who are the first
Cosmopolitan's they're the first people
to think of the world vertically instead
of horizontally they don't think of the
world in terms of territory they know
that forms we could we don't care about
farms in long we don't care about
farmland you can build a fucking
skyscraper who sold the food your nation
needs today you can bring those we
vertically up into the sky that's what
you do in Hong Kong and Singapore
you don't need territory for the first
time in history because we go digital
now and the words becoming vertical so
if you becoming so help me understand
here the process so you're saying the
Palestinians are Spurs are a sort of
virtual nation or something like that
they are the palaces of work would love
these ideas because it explains why
they're frustrated with being pulled
into this instrument Anna Stein conflict
which is a global conflict and it causes
such such stress simply because it's
really about our time we're leaving the
nation and we're now moving into the
global mmm-hmm so it's keep the nation
of Israel to remind us of what the
proper nation should have been like
because they were always the most
successful nationalists anyways and
custom if New York was just nation envy
anyway so we can build the cost of
dominance inside and I'd love to do that
with the Palestinians I'll have to do
that with any people out there there's a
shared identity shared language is
shared history in the old territory
they're perfectly positioned for that
I love Kurds okay so yeah so this is how
you see let's say the the the village or
the I'm not the village the the tribe in
the age of globalization yeah
well Marshall McLuhan he was brilliant
absolutely Marshall McLuhan got it wrong
was when he went to the term the global
village because he didn't see three
paradigms only saw two he saw the
globalization of the village well
between the village and the globe is the
city
Aristotle City okay the cities in
between the urban comes in between so we
first were rural
through permanent settlements in Britain
language became urban through mass media
mass-produced cheap language
mass-produced from the top all the way
down that's we built the modern cities
that's we both sewage systems and
electricity and everything we need for a
city to be sustainable we managed to do
that starting in Europe 300 years ago it
spread across the globe the Chinese had
almost figured out already they could
connect with it and solve the we got
globalization through urbanization but
the one thing left to do is to move into
the virtual the moving to the virtual
which was gil de leurs started working
with in 1960's and 1970's and that's why
i'm adolescent is that philosophers are
they're dealing with what does it mean
to lead the urban I'm moving to the
digital what it means for example that
the city itself changes so the city
stops being horizontal and goes vertical
and vertical is phallic that's what's
interesting about very interesting yeah
yeah to begin with the people who do
best in cities are women
why because women are used to dense
environments because the inner circle
the tribe is a dense environment there's
some women are nitpicking at each other
all the time and checking that they're
in and not out ok the urban environment
is incredibly feminine in that sense
that doesn't means the first way with
digital today was the Instagram and
influences and all these things are very
feminine but they're not gonna last
they're not gonna be sustainable because
the true did it was gone arrived in the
2020s it's gonna kill all of this and
wipe it away and then we're gonna stop
being horizontal instead being vertical
and vertical doesn't necessarily benefit
women more than men he could very much
be more of the outer circle because the
storytelling has to be you need to be
grounded to retry mm-hmm it's vertical
how do you build a skyscraper you build
the sky skirt by spending a lot of time
on building a solid foundation a
basement on the basement you can build
the walls and then you have elevators
all the way up and then you build the
top of the building at the top of the
building is useless if the basement
isn't properly done so even if we all
have access to all the world's
information in our pockets on our smart
phones that information is the best in
your smartphone it's not in your head
meaning the thing you should do today
this build up is to study study
and inside your own brain or so you're
saying you know it's sort of discipline
that's how we create the foundations but
and that needs to come back because we
have this sort of society where
everybody is sort of sucking each
other's tit in it in a sense or well we
created a terrible religion in 1632
called individualism and it's bigger in
America than I was in the world and all
the Americans I meet are kicking and
screaming to keep their damn state
religion which is called Cartesian
individualism and the individual version
of it is called narcissism and it's a
dead religion for God's sake it never
worked okay it was the world of sales
pitches it was the world of marketing
departments it was the world of lying
about what you're doing to try to screw
people and get money out of them so then
make a profit from it it was the
accumulation of capital to try to
impress people nobody's impressed with
that any longer nobody's impressed with
Americans who are fortunate enough to be
wealthy
we don't care okay because of the days
award none of that counts
uh-huh none of that counts you call this
the death of both individual and the
collective
that's replica so it's a return to the
tribe and it's returned to scramble and
it's a return to the monastery and it's
the monastery that wins in a Kotik world
cause I'm moving into a new medieval age
chaos mm-hmm that's the book did it
Olivia
Sanchez said you need to build new
institutions outside of academia and
outside of the churches that we know
today there are more credible than the
churches and those institutions are it
uses the latest technology for small
groups of people just because the
cleverness for connection access to the
best possible information and knowledge
and then the wisdom how to use it wisely
and that's why they build the best teams
on the planet and we're all gonna come
to them and ask for advice and it's
gonna be incredibly expensive to get
device out of them but those
institutions will run the world they
will run truth production for now and
how will they differ from let's say
Google and Facebook and Twitter and all
the massive sort of companies that are
really and the Pearl River Delta in
China are the new landlords they're the
new nobility
they're the nuber so see because the
onda resource they own the data mm-hmm
data is the new capital what used to be
kept before capital was food food
production okay after food production
came capital of the capital comes data
they got the data they don't know how to
use the data Facebook doesn't even know
how to run a fucking customer department
they're autistic arrogant idiots
basically you know all they know has to
collect the data but they are gonna have
to give away the day the data to
somebody who can use it more creatively
there that's gonna take cultural
engineers a culture engineers is the
next section of the nitocris we're gonna
see grow in the 2020s 2030 2040 anybody
who started somewhere between arts and
technology today and is socially
successful is probably well positioned
to become a cultural engineer go to
Burning Man and do products at Burning
Man be successful you probably become a
cultural engineer in the process because
you're in between technology and art
you're in between Silicon Valley Las
Vegas that's a good place to be in
America right now because in between art
and technology most stuff is gonna
happen and that's we're gonna find
creative people that know how to use the
data and you're also gonna find the
people who build and use truth
institutions in your monasteries we're
all sort of access to the data that's
the first thing they trade in because by
having access to the data they can nail
it exactly what's going on in the world
and they can prove it with facts ality
cuz all everything that happens from now
on on our planet possibly the universe
itself is being stored well power as
data I guess yeah
and we're also figuring out that since
information is never lost in the
universe the universe itself is huge
storage machine mm-hmm so all of history
is remembered meaning memory is the big
thing with digital meaning since
everything is there now and available
you can check the data you're basically
a kiss to all the world's libraries at
once and you've got an electron that
goes through all of them and within a
second is reading every book in the
library and part of exactly what you're
looking for and you can improve it
meaning we can stop speculating and
coming up with wild silly fantasies and
in fairy tales which is what television
did with us in the last 50 years and
suddenly television is dead because
isn't real any longer it's a stupid and
silly and childish
well YouTube is throwing at us
increasingly factual reality mm-hmm
again it's phallic remember it's phallic
mm-hmm why because I like storytelling
you cannot garden hunt and you cannot
start war unless you're based in reality
and you've got a foundational
understanding that if I don't know
exactly where I'm at we're hunting I'm
gonna get killed I'm not gonna kill the
animal right so young boys are trained
to think factuality that's exactly why
mathematics is easier for guys
especially when they go into engineering
that's what 93% of the world's tech
startups today we're on by young men
they're doing fine okay
women then run communication departments
very confusingly so and they run product
leadership to do that well in the
together the caring in society that
should be half the value anyways they
can do okay but the men are gonna
kickstart the whole thing and get it
rolling and that's a soccer fan
externally is forcing us individual
that's the exodus we have to do and then
we follow story yeah we get a magical
store turn we can't afford it basically
just for the kids
we can't keep telling magical
storytelling to the entire population
wait a second you remember when Harry
Potter came around yeah yeah you
remember grown-ups just spoke I love
Harry Potter growing up people said well
I'm watching Harry Potter too shouldn't
they have been embarrassed yeah this is
a story for eight-year-olds it's meant
for the kids something for you you're a
dad you're a mum here's the only way
about that kind of storytelling yeah
who's embarrassing to see Harry Potter
becoming a large-scale social phenomenon
you just proved how infantile our
society has become yeah so you're
talking about ways to move out of an
infantile society yeah yeah the diesels
gonna force it on us and either we die
was swept away or we get it and we can
go with it
mm-hmm this is our relationship with the
machines even they become our servants
our happy slaves they serve us or they
just sweep us away